赤焰战场 2
- 宝贝 看看这个  - 强力清洗器?
- Baby, check this out.  - A power washer?
我们需要这样一台
We need one of these.
对
Yeah.
- 清理后院用得上  - 好
- On the patio in the backyard.  - Yeah.
我们去看看玻璃清洁剂吧?
Should we go look at those window treatments?
不要
No.
你想要来一个热狗吗?
Do you want one of these hotdogs?
很好吃呦
They're very good.
宝贝 你真是个居家好男人
Baby, you are a heck of a homemaker.
这样吧? 我们直接去外边吃晚饭吧
You know that? But we could just go to dinner.
哦 其实
Well, you know,
自己动手...
if you don't make it...
丰衣足食
You don't eat it.
对吧? 是个好主意 我给你做晚饭好吗?
You know what? That's a great idea. What if I make you dinner?
我要去拿那个 呃 烤架 又大又亮的那个
I'm gonna go and get that, uh, grill. The big shiny one.
你去拿些虾吧? 大包装的那种
Will you get us some shrimp? The big jumbo kind.
往前走四排 再过去三排的地方
Four down. Three over.
然后回来这里找我 工具区
Come back and find me down here. In tools.
你他妈来干什么?
What the hell are you doing here?
你不回复我的消息
You ignored my messages.
我很快乐
I am happy.
你很绝望
You're desperate.
- 我这样挺好  - 弗兰克 你是在过家家
- I can make this work.  - Frank, you're playing house.
是这样 我退休了 好吧 我很快乐 我们很快乐
Look, I'm retired, okay. I'm happy. We are happy.
弗兰克... 弗兰克...
Frank... Frank...
你已经好几个月没杀人了
You haven't killed anybody in months.
这不是坏事 好不好?
That is not a bad thing, okay?
对大部分人来说这是正常的
That's a positive thing for a lot of people.
独行侠 我需要你 他们来了 我能感觉到
Kemosabe, I need you. They're coming. I can feel it.
你快把我逼疯了 马文
You are driving me nuts, Marvin.
听着 如果你愿意的话 可以带上那个女孩
Listen, if it makes you feel better, bring the girl.
我不会带她去任何地方 明白吗?
I'm not gonna bring the girl anywhere, all right?
不会带我去哪?
Don't bring the girl where?
哦 我们只是随便谈谈
Oh, we're just catching up.
马文也在这 我刚好碰到马文
Marvin's here. I just bumped into Marvin.
我们要去哪?
Where are we going?
哪也不去 走吧 快关门了
No, come on. They're gonna close.
很高兴见到你 马文
Good to see you, Marvin.
- 很高兴见到你  - 弗兰克
- Good to see you.  - Frank.
你知道你想的
You know you want to.
- 不想  - 行了
- No.  - Come on.
最后一次机会 弗兰克
Last chance, Frank.
我要带萨拉回家
I'm taking Sarah home.
保重
Stay safe.
- 哦 我真的很想...  - 当然 是这样的 宝贝
- Well, I really wanted to be...  - Of course, it is, honey.
你再也不能身处险境了
You are never gonna be in danger ever again.
我们都不知道是怎么回事
We don't even know what happened.
我们都不知道那里有什么人
We don't know who's in there.
我该怎么保护你?
How am I gonna protect you?
嘿 他可是你最好的朋友
Hey. He was your best friend.
对吧?
Okay?
来吧
Come on.
喔
Wow.
他看起来还像活着一样
He still looks so lifelike.
他没死
He's not dead.
宝贝 别这样 哭出来吧 别这样...
Honey, don't do that. Just let your feelings out. Don't...
不 真的
No. Really.
他干过好多次了
He does this a lot.
真的?
Really?
别 给我 把针给我 给我
No, come on. Give me the pin. Give me the pin.
行了 宝贝 我们去坐下吧 走
Come on, sweetie. Let's go sit down. Come on.
- 来吧  - 我该吻他
- Come on.  - I should kiss him.
是 吻吧 真的吗?
Yeah, go ahead. Do you want to?
还是去坐下吧 走 走了 宝贝
Let's go sit down. Come on. Come on, sweetie.
此时此刻 是否有人愿意走上前来
At this time, we'll open the floor to anyone
来为逝者讲几句
who wishes to say a few words about the deceased.
宝贝...
Babe...
或者 说说往事?
Share a memory, perhaps?
再或者 念首诗 或者一首歌词
Perhaps, a poem. A song lyric.
有人要来吗?
Anyone?
你可以的
You can do it.
先生?
Sir?
马文他
Marvin was
与众不同
different.
他是个
He was
神枪手
a very good shot.
有人说他
Some would say that
是妄想症
he was paranoid.
不过中情局给你服用了超过十年的迷幻药
But you have to expect a little of that when the CIA's dosing you with LSD
这情况很正常
for a little more than a decade.
他布置炸弹的速度
He could wire a bomb
比我见过的任何人都快
faster than anybody I ever met.
摩尔多瓦善良的人们永远
The good people of Moldova will always
都应该记得马文的恩德
be in Marvin's debt.
他真的是个好朋友
He was a really good friend.
非常好
Really good.
我会怀念他的
I'm gonna miss him.
会的
Gonna miss him.
- 我们得搬家  - 加拿大?
- We have to move.  - Canada?
高地 很好的猎杀地区 是个小农场
High ground. Good kill zones. It's a little farm.
- 农场? 可以 放牧的那种?  - 对 是的
- A farm? Like, to farm on?  - Yeah. Yeah.
还可以 种庄稼那种?
Like, with crops?
对 挺有意思的
Yeah. It could be fun.
听着 宝贝...
Listen, babe...
据说在经历过大的悲伤之后...
You know they say it's really important not to make big...
最好不要做重大的决定
life-altering decisions right after a loss.
如果他们能追到马文 他们就能追到你也能追到我
If they can get to Marvin, they can get to you and they can get to me.
他们是谁?
Who are they?
去安全房
Go to the safe house.
看着我 去安全房
Look at me. Go to the safe house.
我会去找你的 好吗?
I'll come find you, okay?
- 我不要离开你  - 听话...
- I'm not leaving you.  - Listen...
不会有事的
It'll be all right.
你们是?
What is it?
摩西先生...
Mr. Moses...
海军罪案调查处要讯问你
They want to debrief you at a Yankee White Facility.
还带了狙击手?
Is that your sniper?
因为你被标记为"极度危险退休人员"
You're flagged Retired Extremely Dangerous.
海军罪案调查处
嗨 你好
Hi, there.
呃 我的委托人弗兰克·摩西在这
Um, my client Frank Moses is here.
他是一名美国公民被未经司法程序而非法扣留于此
He's an American citizen being detained illegally without due process.
- 你选的吗? 上衣真好看  - 哦 谢谢
- You know what? That is a lovely blazer.  - Oh, thank you.
别客气
You're welcome.
抱歉 我不清楚
I'm sorry, I have no idea.
我帮你叫斯奈德先生
But let me get Mr Snyder for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我能帮你什么吗?
How can I help you?
- 哦 嗨 你好 抱歉 你叫什么?  - 约翰·斯奈德
- Oh, hi, there. I'm sorry. What is your name?  - John Snyder.
约翰 还有你呢? 我还不知道你叫什么
John. You know what? I didn't get your name.
- 哦 我叫凯丽  - 嗨 凯丽
- Oh, it's Kelly.  - Hi, Kelly.
约翰...
John...
约翰... 约翰!
John... John!
你如果不想跟凯丽一样下场
Unless you want to end up like Kelly,
就马上告诉我弗兰克·摩西在哪
I suggest you tell me where Frank Moses is right now.
快!
Now!
在审讯室
In interrogation.
啊!
Ah!
我这里有一份文件称你在冷战时期执行过特殊任务
I got a document right here that says that you have a special interest in the Cold War.
我们知道那个时候 你在俄罗斯过了一段苦日子
We know that back in the day, you spent an awful lotta time in Russia.
我只需要知道你对"龙葵行动"知道些什么
I just need to know what you know about Project Nightshade.
我真的什么都不知道
I really don't know anything about it.
什么声音?
What the hell is that?
微型冲锋枪 距离200码
Small arms gunfire, 200 yards.
盯着他
Watch him.
100码
100 yards.
他们是来杀我们的
They're coming to kill us.
打开我的手铐
Get me outta these cuffs.
恕难从命 先生
I can't do that, sir.
你带着钥匙 对吧?
You have the key, right?
举起手来!
Hands up!
还有50尺
50 feet.
你不给我打开手铐的话 他们会把我们都杀掉的
They're gonna kill us both, if you don't get me outta these cuffs.
来吧
Come on.
弗兰克·摩西
Frank Moses.
其实要论军功 你是我心目中的英雄
You know, coming up through the ranks, you were my hero.
不过岁月不饶人 再厉害也不得不服老吧
Given enough time, I guess everyone cracks.
对吧 弗兰克?
Huh, Frank?
- 你是谁?  - 我?
- Who are you?  - Me?
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
我是政府雇佣来获取情报的人
I'm the guy the government hires to get information.
而且我可以进行我认为合理的任何形式的刑讯逼供
And I'm allowed to use any form of torture I deem fit.
而且如果你不开口我会对萨拉用刑
And I will torture Sarah until you speak.
说到萨拉 我喜欢看着她
Speaking of Sarah, I love watching her
躺在浴缸里刮腿毛
shave her legs in the tub.
让我想起了我在刚果遇到的那些比利时佣兵
Kinda reminds me of these Belgian mercs I met in the Congo.
为了逼供他们会活剥人皮
They would skin people alive to get them to talk.
你知道他们总哪里开始剥吗?
And do you know where they started?
猜猜
Guess.
从脚踝 跟你的萨拉一样
At the ankles. Just like your Sarah.
那么...
So...
要么你给我我要的情报...
You either give me the information that I need to know...
要么我毫不留情得把你的女人凌迟了
Or I'm gonna fillet your girl from head to toe with no mercy.
很好
Awesome.
喔
Wow.
对一个退休人员来说身手不错 可是你难道...
Pretty good for a retired guy. But are you...
一二三四五六...
1-2-3-4-5-6...
七对一 你还被铐着 手无寸铁也可以吗?
7-on-1 cuffed with no weapon good?
他妈的...
Son of a...
上 快 快 快!
Go. Go, go, go!
打伤就行了 留活口
Shoot him, but don't kill him.
好吧 打死也可以 包抄上去
All right, kill him. Spray it up.
弗兰克 这是你的最后机会
Frank, this is your last chance.
开火
Fire.
进去! 快!
Get in there! Go!
该死
Shit.
马文!
Marvin!
- 你快把我逼疯了!  - 我带钥匙来了
- You're driving me crazy!  - I brought the key.
你又装死
You faked your death.
- 该走了  - 我们走
- Gotta go.  - Let's go.
走吧
Gotta go.
你知道这给我惹了多大麻烦吗!
You have no idea what you put me through!
哦! 谢天谢地 你没事
Oh! Thank God, you're okay.
不!
No!
- 你来干什么?  - 马文带我来的 从安全房
- What are you doing here?  - Marvin brought me. From the house.
难道所有人都疯了吗?
Has everybody lost their mind?
- 马文 你不能把那样的女人扯进来  - 我总要知道你没事 对吧?
- Marv, you don't bring a girl like that here.  - I had to see if you were okay, didn't I?
宝贝!
Honey!
- 我觉得...  - 怎么了?
- I thought...  - What?
记得我们说过你不能参与这些吗?
Remember when we had that conversation about how you were gonna lay low?
你也没说哪些不能参与
You don't get to tell me when to lay.
我想说 我不是那个意思
I mean, I'm not saying that.
别说了 别说了 别... 不
Stop. Just don't. Just don't... No.
- 你现在生我气了?  - 你对我像瓷娃娃一样
- You're mad at me now?  - You treat me like a china doll.
弗兰克 我能给你一些关于女人的建议吗?
Frank, can I give you a little advice about women?
不能! 完全不能!
No! Absolutely not!
这样 你应该扪心自问
Listen, you gotta ask yourself,
一个那样的女人跟你这样一个货在一起图什么?
what is a girl like that doing with a guy like you?
肯定不是因为你长得帅
It ain't for your looks.
听着 我要开枪了 打烂你的肝
You know, I will shoot you. I will shoot you in the liver.
冒险 浪漫 危险 行动 这才是你能为伴侣分享的东西
Adventure, romance, danger, activities you can share as a couple.
是你骗我的事
It's about you lying to me.
弗兰克...
Frank...
你在我的葬礼上哭我很感动
I was very touched that you cried at my funeral.
没有的事
That's not true.
我在你葬礼没有哭
I didn't cry at your funeral.
我从来不哭
I'm no crier.
九十六个小时之前 有人在网络上发布了一份文件
Ninety-six hours ago, somebody posted a document on the Internet
称你我曾经在79年参与过一个叫"龙葵"的行动
that said you and I took part in an operation called Nightshade back in '79.
所以你才会装死?
That's why you fake died?
是 这引起了极大关注
Yeah. The chatter went through the roof.
所以所有这些追你们的人认为你们知道一些
So everybody's after you for something they think you know
你们其实并不知道的事?
that you don't even know at all?
哦 天呐! 蜘蛛!
Oh, my God! Spiders!
宝贝 你应该离开去一个我不知道的地方
Honey, you need to go to ground and it's best I don't know where.
不 我哪也不去
Yeah, I'm not going anywhere.
- 只花现金 别打电话 别联系  - 谢谢 这样...
- Cash only. No calls. No contacts.  - Thanks. Look...
你在外边溜来溜去跟幽昧的国际危险女性一起拯救世界的时候
I'm not hanging out in some bunker while you slink around and save the planet
我才不要躲在某个地堡里
with dusky international femme fatales.
- 幽昧?  - 幽暗 烟熏的意思
- Dusky?  - Dark, smoldering.
我知道什么意思 马文
I know what it means, Marvin.
有你在场的情况下
It's hard to be the kinda person I have to be right now
我做不了我自己 也办不成该办的事
and do the kinda things that I'm going to have to do while you're here.
这会对我们有好处的
This is gonna be good for us.
我们要做什么?
What are we doing?
面对吧 可伦坡 一切都变了
Let's face it, Columbo, things were getting a little stale.
喔 妈妈在饭桌上扇了爸爸一巴掌哇
Wow. Mommy just slapped Daddy at the dinner table.
后备箱里有个人?
Is there a human being in the trunk?
是
Yeah.
是谁 马文?
Who is it, Marvin?
他是军情六处的一位高级主管
He's a Senior Director of Military Intelligence.
我已经折磨他好多天了
I've been caramelizing his onions for a couple of days.
怎么折磨?
Caramelizing how?
三勺酸液和很多老鼠
With three tabs of acid and a lot of rats.
啊!
Dang!
五角大楼
11个人死了 5个是联邦调查局的 国防部长想要一个简报?
Eleven people dead. Five FBI. And the SecDef wants a briefing?
你是干嘛吃的
You were brought in to contain this.
冷静点
Calm down.
我不信这么多年了 这件事还会找上我
I can't believe this is coming back on me after so many years.
将军 摩西和博格斯已经被彻底孤立了
General, Moses and Boggs have been completely isolated.
联邦调查局要以涉嫌凶杀逮捕他们
The FBI is seeking them for the murders.
国土安全局已经正式接到通知 说他们是恐怖分子
Homeland has been informed that they are officially domestic terrorists.
这样做靠谱吗?
Is that gonna work?
是的
Yes.
问题是只要网上有那个文件
The problem is with that document surfacing on the Internet,
所有人都会去追寻龙葵的下落
all the players will be coming after Nightshade.
纸包不住火
It'll open the book on this.
我要给国防部长打电话 我们得把这件事公布于众
I'm calling SecDef. We need to go public.
将军...
General...
没有人可以把这件事公布于众
Nobody's going public.
我们需要为摩西制定一个新计划
We need a new plan for Moses.
我需要你批准一个专家参与此事
I need you to approve a specialist.
什么专家? 中央情报局的?
What? CIA?
我已经试过了 他们对付不了那些家伙
It's been tried, sir. Didn't work so well for those guys.
去请韩秋白 他是最厉害的
Han Cho Bai. He's the best.
那就去吧
Do it.
香港
衣服也脱下来
Suit, too.
好了 他没问题
Okay, he's clean.
没搞错吧?
Seriously?
请坐 韩先生
Sit down, Mr. Han.
你的安保措施不错嘛
Your security is impressive.
他是一个商业伙伴
A business associate.
胡里奥·阿尔瓦兹·费尔南德斯
Julio Alvarez Fernandes.
很难接近
Very difficult to get close to.
当然 这必须处理得像一个意外事故
Of course, it must appear like an accident.
没问题 除了一件事
Not a problem. Except for one thing.
嗯?
Mmm?
费尔南德斯先生出价更高
Mr. Fernandes pays better.
喂?
Yeah?
目标是谁?
Who's the target?
噢 是你的一个老朋友 弗兰克·摩西
Oh, it's an old pal of yours. Frank Moses.
报应到了 弗兰克
Karma is a bitch, Frank.
伦敦 军情六处总部
这又是怎么了?
What is this?
维基解密文件上有一个标志
There's a watchword flag on a WikiLeaks document.
表示它是最高机密文件
It's coded Priority One Alpha Seven.
- 有个叫龙葵的东西  - 闭嘴!
- Something called Nightshade.  - Shut up!
快出去
Get out.
给我找维多利亚·温斯洛
Find me Victoria Winslow.
菲利普斯主任?
Director Philips?
嗯...
Um...
我这里有客人
I'm with someone right now.
看来你还是闲不住啊
Keeping busy, I see.
游手好闲 造恶之源
Idle hands do the Devil's work.
没错
Yes.
我知道你能接近弗兰克·摩西
I understand you can get close to Frank Moses.
没错
Yes.
军情六处有任务给你
MI6 has a job for you.
如果你想活命 就接受它
If you want to stay alive, you're going to accept it.
是时候选择立场了 维多利亚
It's time to choose sides, Victoria.
他们在哪儿教会你们这些东西的?
Where do they teach you guys this stuff?
看说明书 自学
Manuals, mostly.
嗯
Mmm.
一些东西是教不来的
Some of this stuff you just can't teach.
哇
Wow.
这不是很酷吗?
Isn't this cool?
我们一起完成任务
We're on a mission together.
你知道现在有多少人想要杀死我们吗?
Do you have any idea how many people are trying to kill us right now?
我们都明白 这里才是你应该在的地方
You and I both know that this is where you belong.
就在这儿
Right here. In the thick of it.
美人儿说得对 弗兰克
Pussy Cat's right, Frank.
走吧
Here we go.
小心脚下
Watch your step.
怎么了?
What?
噢
Oh.
拜托!
Come on!
- 这是从哪儿来的?  - 嗯... 马文给我的
- Where did you get this?  - Um... Marvin.
- 你给她枪?  - 这是美国 弗兰克
- You gave her a gun?  - It is America, Frank.
除了我大家都有枪
Everyone else has a gun.
她根本不会用
She has no idea what to do with this.
我会用
I know exactly what to do with it.
哦!
Ow!
别让小白碰火器
You don't give fire to a kitten.
你怎么不再给她点炸药呢 马文?
Why don't you just give her some dynamite, Marvin?
西格这枪没保险哈?
No external safety on the Sig?
把刚才告诉我的再跟他说一遍
Tell him what you told me.
冷战期间
At the height of the Cold War,
美国一个将军炮制了龙葵
Nightshade was cooked up by a rogue US general
想利用它对苏联进行先发打击
as a first strike capability against the Soviets.
- 说完了 我能走了吗?  - 说完了?
- That's it. Can I go?  - That's it?
- 想来点这个配胡椒吗?  - 不 好吧! 冷战期间
- You want a little pepper with that?  - No, okay! At the height of the Cold War,
通过外交邮件 一个兆吨当量的核装置
a megaton-yield device was smuggled into Moscow
被偷运到莫斯科 拆开来运进来的 然后这东西丢了 就这些
in diplomatic pouches, piece by piece, and then the weapon was lost. That's it.
你们在莫斯科弄丢了一件核武器?
You lost a nuke in Moscow?
制造它的科学家是爱德华·白利 就这些
The scientist was Edward Bailey. That's it.
怎么了?
What?
我犯了一个错误
I made a mistake.
爱德华·白利是一个天才物理学家
Edward Bailey was a genius physicist who built some of the greatest stuff
他在冷战时期制造过了很多杰作
during the Cold War.
中子弹 粒子束武器 神经毒气 非常厉害
Neutron bombs, particle beam weapons, nerve gas. Excellent nerve gas.
他是大规模杀伤武器方面的明星
He was a rock star of conceptual mass killing.
他们称他"死神达芬奇"
They called him "The Da Vinci of Death."
那时我们被安排去保护他在莫斯科的安全
We were the security detail assigned to getting him in and out of Moscow safely.
然后呢?
What happened?
我们以为他是安全的 苏联政府策划了一场汽车爆炸 抓到了他
We thought he was secure. The Soviets got him with a car bomb.
这都怪我
It was my fault.
他死了
He's dead.
我们是逃是战?
Run or fight?
我们只有这个维基解密网页
All we've got is this WikiLeaks page off the Internet.
从一个巴黎的IP地址发表的
Out of a Paris IP.
嗯 可能是巴黎的任何人
Hmm. Paris could be anybody.
等一下 等一下 后退一秒钟
Wait. Wait. Scroll back down for a second.
- 那是什么?  - 噢
- What is that?  - Oh.
嗯...
Uh...
咖啡的污渍?
Coffee stain?
嗯 是酒渍
Mmm. Wine.
青蛙
Frog.
什么?
What?
没事
We're okay.
是找你的
Your number.
喂
Yeah.
军情六处刚刚聘请我去杀你
MI6 has just given me a contract to kill you.
很显然 你涉嫌核恐怖分子 以及谋杀
Apparently, you're guilty of nuclear terrorism, murder,
并且是国际刑警的头号通缉犯
and you're number one on Interpol's Most Wanted.
那你说什么了?
What did you say?
哦 我说"可以啊"
Oh, I said "Yes. "
你知道 他们给的钱很多
You know, the money's good.
总之 就算我不做 其他人也会做
And anyway, if I don't do it, somebody else will.
哦 你应该知道美国也在派其他人去杀你
Oh, and you should know the Americans are sending someone also.
谁?
Who?
韩
Han.
糟透了 不是吗?
It's bad, isn't it?
- 你身边那个是马文吗?  - 对 还有萨拉
- Is that Marvin?  - Yes. And Sarah.
噢! 代我向他们问好
Aw! Send them my love, will you?
他们要把我逼疯了
They're driving me crazy.
马文给她一支枪
Marvin gave her a gun.
- 上膛了吗?  - 对!上膛了!
- Was it loaded?  - Yes! Yes!
你正被枪指着呢?
Are you being controlling?
没有!
No!
男女关系一定要把握好机会啊
You have to take chances in a relationship.
你得主动点
You have to be supportive.
我不想让她参加 我只要她安全
I don't need her to fit in. I just need her to be safe.
去租张碟 "脏舞"就行了 告诉她你爱她
Just rent. Dirty Dancing, tell her you love her.
在你还能享受生活的时候就赶紧去享受
You know, it's important to enjoy life while you still can.
维多利亚刚刚接受了中情六处委托 来杀我们
Victoria just accepted a contract from MI6 to kill all three of us.
你认为她不会那么做的 是吧? 弗兰克 她不会那么做的?
You don't think she'd do that, do you? Frank, you don't think she'd do that?
她是我们的朋友
She's a friend.
弗兰克 你傻吗? 你从没受雇去杀一个朋友吗?
Frank, what, are you stupid? You never took a contract out to kill a friend?
她打电话只是警告我们
She called to give us fair warning.
拜托 还有一件事呢
Come on. There's one more thing.
韩才是最大的麻烦
Han just went number one.
还不如直接把老二泡在蜂蜜里
Why don't they just dip our balls in honey
塞到蚂蚁窝里去算了?
and stake us to an ant farm?
快点
Come on.
喔! 疯狂的老混蛋
Whoa! Crazy old bastard.
弗兰克 你觉得自己老了吗?
Frank, do you feel old?
- 没有啊  - 我也是
- Not really.  - Me neither.
我有时候确实有点疯狂
I mean, crazy sometimes, I guess.
韩是谁?
Who's Han?
一个跟情报局作对的韩国人
Korean. Counter-intel.
弗兰克把他抓进监狱关了几年
Frank put him in jail for a few years.
那我们就应该怕他了 是吧?
We should be super-scared of him, huh?
没错 他是世界上最好的职业杀手
Yes. He is the best contract killer in the world.
我找到了一个销声匿迹近20年的身份
I've got a hit off an old alias, silent for almost 20 years.
他在逃脱追捕
He's dodging watch lists.
没错 他明早九点乘私人飞机从泰特波罗去巴黎
Bingo. Private flight to Paris scheduled for 09:00 out of Teterboro.
找到宾馆 查到分布图 和经理换岗的时间表
Find their hotel. Get blueprints and workups on the day and night managers.
让万斯在机场等我们
Have Vance meet us on the ground.
新泽西州 泰特波罗
他们在下一层 两个相邻的房间 监视运行正常
They're one floor down. Two adjoining rooms. Surveillance is almost up and running.
这比我想像的简单多了
This is going to be easier than I thought.
嗨 请讲
Hello. Speaking.
是的
Yes.
- 他们在哪儿?  - 刚才还在
- Where are they?  - They were here.
他们一点才定了客房服务
They ordered room service at 1:00.
你说"飞机准备好了"什么意思?
What do you mean, "The plane is prepped"?
我觉得有人偷了你的飞机
I think someone stole your plane.
我真的很期待去杀了他
I'm really going to enjoy killing him.
给我弄支强力点的枪
Get me a gun that really hurts.
这个人怎么样?
So how good is this guy?
韩是世界上最好的职业杀手
Han is the best contract killer in the world.
弗兰克的处境非常非常危险
Let's just say that Frank is in some very, very deep dog doo.
- 他杀不了我的  - 没错
- He's not gonna kill me.  - Yeah.
- 没有人能杀掉弗兰克·摩西  - 对!
- Nobody kills Frank Moses.  - Right!
对于不喜欢的人 他会折磨很久
The people he really doesn't like, he tortures for a long time first.
我们能不能集中精力去抓青蛙?
Can we just focus on trying to catch The Frog?
好吧 目标捕获及处置行动计划是什么?
Okay. What's the action plan for target acquisition and rendition?
马文?
Marvin?
以后不要再教她东西!
Quit teaching her stuff!
好极了
Nice.
你觉得世上最贵的葡萄酒多少钱一瓶?
What do you think the most expensive bottle of wine in the world costs?
1847年的依坤宫葡萄酒
Chateau d'Yquem 1847.
也许世界上只有五六瓶 非常贵
Maybe five, six, maybe, bottles left in the world. It's pretty pricey.
或许我们应该找一瓶那个酒 然后带着酒去抓青蛙
Maybe we should get a bottle of that wine and try to catch The Frog with it.
巴黎
天呐 这里好浪漫啊!
My God, this is so romantic!
过来 把头低下来
Come here. Keep your head down.
我们一定要去圣路易岛吃冰淇淋
But we have to go to the Ile Saint-Louis for gelato.
不行
I don't think so.
是吗? 那么...
Really? What about the...
- 弗兰克 那是...  - 是她
- Frank, is that...  - Mmm... hmm.
你好 弗兰克
Hello, Frank.
- 你后来见过她吗?  - 没
- Have you seen her since?  - Nope.
天呐 我想死你了
God, I've missed you.
她是谁?
Who is she?
她是个麻烦
Trouble.
近来怎么样?
How are things?
对呀 弗兰克 近来怎么样?
Yeah, Frank, how are things?
萨拉...
Sarah...
这位是卡塔亚
This is Katja.
没错 嗨
Yeah. Hi.
我需要跟你谈一谈 立刻马上
I need to speak with you. Immediately.
这究竟是怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
卡塔亚·彼得洛维奇 俄罗斯反情报局的
Katja Petrokovich. Russian Counter-Intelligence.
我认为我们应该听听她要说什么
I think we should hear what she has to say.
弗兰克...
Frank...
你不知道之前的事 那时候她和弗兰克还很年轻
You don't know the half of it. She and Frank were young.
他不知道她在为俄罗斯工作
And he didn't have the slightest idea she was working for the Russians.
她是弗兰克·摩西的克星
She's Frank Moses' kryptonite.
我喜欢你的光头 弗兰克
I like you with no hair, Frank.
光头男人很性感 有男人味
Bald men are so sexy. Virile.
喔
Wow.
她很可爱
She's cute.
你们在哪认识的? 内布拉斯加?
Where did you find her? Nebraska?
- 堪萨斯  - 堪萨斯
- Kansas.  - Kansas.
你想要跟我谈什么?
So what was it you wanted to talk to me about?
我不愿相信美国在莫斯科设置了
I would like to believe that the US didn't plant
大规模杀伤性武器 但我做不到
a weapon of mass-destruction in Moscow. But I don't.
你为什么来巴黎?
Why are you in Paris?
我们每年秋天都会为了罢工季来这里
We come every fall for Strike Season
- 还有这儿的好天气  - 哦?
- and for the weather.  - Oh?
好吧 美国好像认为你是核恐怖分子
Well, the US seems to think you're nuclear terrorists.
俄方想要拥有它
Russia wants complete access.
你要么现在就同意 或者我把你直接交给美国政府
You agree now or I'll hand you over to the US government.
为啥不杀了她?
Can't we just kill her?
抱歉离开下 我能跟你说几句话么?
Excuse me for one second. Can I talk to you?
- 啥? 哦 行  - 过来下
- What? Oh. Uh-huh. Sure thing.  - Come here for a minute.
- 你知道 我很震惊  - 我懂
- You know, I was shocked.  - I got it.
我知道 她都用舌头数了你有几颗牙了
Yeah, I know. She was kinda counting your teeth with her tongue.
确实有点
A little, yeah.
她现在能离开了么?
Can she go now?
别无选择 我们需要她的帮助
We don't really have a choice. We need her to help us.
我保证我俩之间没什么
I promise there is nothing between us.
长官 这家伙什么都没给我们提供
No, sir. This guy's not giving us anything.
网站已经关闭了
Website's been scrubbed.
国家安全局截获了从巴黎到克里姆林宫的一条情报
NSA intercepted a dispatch to the Kremlin from Paris.
摩西正在追踪一个叫"青蛙"的人
Moses is going after someone called "The Frog."
"青蛙"
The Frog.
管他叫"青蛙"是因为他是法国人吗?
So they call him "The Frog" because he's French?
不是
No.
不 他之前在克格勃总部的自来水中
No, he poisoned the water supply at KGB headquarters
下了亚马逊树蛙毒
with the Amazon tree frog poison.
他之前收集这些树上小动物肯定花了不少时间
He must have been wiping those little tree humpers for years.
致使1600人瘫痪 还带走我们所有的机密
Incapacitated 1,600 people and left with every secret we had.
这家伙一直靠卖情报赚钱
You know, the guy makes a fortune selling information.
他知道得太多了 连美国人都不敢动他
He knows so much even the US won't touch him.
难的就是生擒他
The hard part is gonna be taking him alive.
- 超好喝  - 酒就是酒
- Superb.  - Wine is wine.
我要买美国防空安全协议
I want to buy American air defense protocols.
恐怖分子怎么就不懂得欣赏勃艮第?
Why is it terrorists never appreciate Burgundy?
听着 想必你还不清楚
Look, I don't think you know
你在和谁打交道呢
who you're dealing with.
嘘 稍等下
Shh! Excusez-moi.
嗯
Hmm.
确定了 就是他 青蛙
Confirmed. It's him. It's The Frog.
别盯着他 对吧?
Just don't look at him, right?
动作自然点
Well, just act natural.
不管你干嘛 别直盯着他的眼睛
And whatever you do, don't look him right in the eyes.
明白
Check.
记着 别直盯着他
Remember, don't look right at him.
笨蛋!
Idiot!
- 马文 你没事吧?  - 没事
- Marvin, you all right?  - Yeah.
好吧 带她离开这
All right. Get her outta here.
- 何时?  - 现在!
- When?  - Now!
弄辆车!
Get a car!
那是...
Is that...
抢他们前面去!
Cut them off!
这主意不好!
This is not a good idea!
不能让她追到!
She's not gonna get there first!
靠边!
Sidewalk!
- 好!  - 不!
- Yes!  - No!
爽!
Yes!
玩我 笨蛋!
Happy trans, bozo!
你不觉得我们应该...
Don't you think we should let...
闭上你的嘴 马文!
Shut your pie hole, Marvin!
你不觉得我们应该...
Don't you think we should let...
嘘!
Hush!
过来了!
Incoming!
要命啊! 靠边!
Bastard! Sidewalk!
天啊...
What the...
她真靠谱
She's fine.
看到了
Got him.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
有办法
Got him.
看! 她在干嘛?
Look! What is she doing?
我求...
I'm begging...
好 好 瞧我的
Yeah, yeah. I got this.
我一定做得到
I so got this.
我好恨她
I hate her so much.
你在浪费时间!
You're wasting your time!
你们一定会为此付出代价的
You're going to regret this more than you can possibly imagine.
嗨
Hey.
你知道我们是谁么?
You know who we are?
当然
Yes, of course.
跟我们说说龙葵
Tell us about Nightshade.
你觉得我会投靠你们这些喜欢米老鼠的美国霸权主义
You think I'm going to roll over for you hegemonic Mickey Mouse-loving Americans?
别把米老鼠扯进来
Leave Mickey out of it.
1947年柏图斯酒庄?
1947 Petrus?
是 这瓶相当...
Yes. That one's rather...
上帝!
God's sake!
1945年
1945.
等 等 这瓶...
Wait, wait, wait! That bottle...
我们怎么能找到它?
How do we find it?
不可能 龙葵是疯子的一个阴谋
Never! Nightshade was the plot of lunatics.
我过去跟你们一样 被洗脑被恐吓
I used to be like you. Driven by ideology and fear
从不思考这个世界多么美丽和可爱
with no love of what's beautiful in the world.
我才不信你们这些畜生!
I can't trust animals like you!
随你们便
Do what you will.
死很容易
Death is easy.
这无关目的地 而是旅程
It's not about the destination. It's about the journey.
死亡是俄罗斯的一种艺术形式
Death is an art form in Russia.
让人生不如死的方法太多了
There are so many ways to take a man to bits.
要不要试试车臣整容? 往下按住他!
Shall we start with a Chechen facelift? Hold him down!
停! 停！
Stop! Stop it!
我们就是这么来的
This is how we do it.
拜托 你那么勇敢
Please. You're so brave.
但你要明白
But you have to understand
我们做这些是有原因的 还有...
we're doing this for the right reasons. And this...
为此放弃你的生命不值得
This isn't worth your life.
你肯定还生有所求
You must have something to live for.
艺术
Art.
美酒
Wine.
女人?
Women?
哎
Hey.
帮帮我们
Help us.
我们需要这个情报
We need this information.
你在帮我们拯救世界 拜托
You'll be helping us save the world. Please.
嗯
Mmm.
因为你 我帮了
You, I'll help.
让一下
Excuse me.
谢谢
Thank you.
你没戏
And you can suck it.
宝贝? 甜心?
Baby? Honey?
认真的么? 你跟她搞一起了?
Seriously? You hooked up with that?
了不起的女人
What a woman.
这两件裙子一样的吗?
Is that the same dress?
在你看来它们是一样的?
They look the same to you?
没人叫过我是弗兰克·摩西的克星
No one ever called me Frank Moses' kryptonite.
弗兰克疯狂的爱着你
Frank's crazy about you.
我从没见过他那么怕失去你
I've never seen him afraid of anything except losing you.
可我是不是正在毁了他的生活?
What if I'm ruining his life?
弗兰克是那种头脑简单欲求单一的动物
Frank is a very simple creature with very simple needs.
好吗? 就只是杀人
Okay? It's killing,
吃饱
eating,
一夜情
sexting,
吃饱...
eating...
杀人 我猜
Killing, I guess.
你想说什么?
What's your point?
我不敢相信你亲了青蛙
I can't believe you kissed The Frog.
我亲过很多只青蛙
Well, I've kissed a lotta frogs.
- 我有东西给你  - 什么?
- I got something for ya.  - What is it?
青蛙存款保险柜的钥匙
The key to The Frog's security deposit box.
- 从哪弄的?  - 法国里昂信贷银行
- From?  - Credit Lyonnais.
宝宝 我有个要求
Baby, I have a request.
嗯
Uh-huh.
今晚和我出去吃个饭如何?
How would you feel about going out to dinner with me tonight?
- 嗯  - 怎么说这里是巴黎
- Hmm.  - It is Paris, after all.
好啊 太好了!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
待在这 我就回来
Stay here. I'll be right back.
弗兰克 我需要你
I need you, Frank.
现在不行
It's not a good time.
我们有个线人提供了一些真实情报
One of our old assets has some real information.
他现在要跟我们见面
He needs to meet with us right now.
不
Nah.
弗兰克 你在干嘛? 她是你的克星 你在干嘛?
Frank, what are you doing? She's kryptonite. What are you doing?
- 我能应付  - 你确定?
- I'll handle it.  - Are you sure?
嗯
Yeah.
不好意思 有点工作要做
It's not okay. It's just some work.
- 别这样 多没意思  - 去吧 和你的俄国情人工作去吧
- No, it's not fun.  - Go. You and Svetlana, you work it out.
我保证我准时回来陪你吃饭
I promise you that I will be back in time for dinner.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
保护好她
Keep her safe.
弗兰克 我们之间怎么了?
What happened to us, Frank?
- 这个...  - 嗯
- Well...  - Hmm.
你背叛了我
You betrayed me.
你离开了我 差点杀了我
You set me up. Tried to kill me.
我差点杀了你
I tried to kill you.
美好的旧时光啊 不是么?
They were good times, weren't they?
你知道么 如果你让我背叛我的国家
You know, if you'd asked me to betray my country,
我就不得不下狠心的
you know I would have.
好的 女士
Yes, Madam.
天啊
My God.
你知道么 我曾去找过你
You know, I looked you up once.
那时你住在洛杉矶的一间小屋里
You were in a bungalow in Los Angeles.
门前种着一大片玫瑰花
There were roses out in front.
但我那时没勇气
But I lost my nerve.
你想怎么样?
So what do you want?
弗兰克 记忆里都是和你共事 都是纪律束缚
It was all about work with you, Frank. Rules.
不关纪律
Not rules.
对错
Right and wrong.
你知道么 尽管我当时有自己的个人感情
You know, it's harder for me not to follow orders.
但我不能不遵从命令
Despite my personal feelings.
感觉超越一切甚至对错
But feelings don't matter any more than right or wrong.
但是命令却有对错
Orders matter.
命令?
Orders?
俄罗斯要从这拿一些东西
Russia will handle things from here.
弗兰克 我要拿走那把钥匙
I'm taking the key, Frank.
我不会让你拿走的
I can't let that happen.
不会?
No?
我胳膊没知觉了
I can't feel my arms.
在堪萨斯好好享受
Enjoy Kansas.
嗯
Hmm.
他晕了
He's out.
他好像醒了
He might be awake.
正好 那他能感觉到了
Oh, good. So he can feel it.
你整个职业生涯有被人下过药吗?
Did you ever, ever in your entire career let yourself get drugged?
你还喜欢她!
You still like her!
现在她拿走了钥匙!
And now she has the key!
她没拿走这把钥匙 她只是拿了一把钥匙
She doesn't have the key. She has a key.
什么?
What?
我知道这女人肯定会像弹班卓琴一样玩弄他
I knew she would play him like a banjo at an Ozark Hoedown.
所以我收好了
So I have the key.
水
Water.
我是待了多久?
How long was I out for?
有一些是他的
Some of it's his.
马文 你也有份?
Et tu Marvin?
弗兰克 潮流是生活中唯一不变的
Style is the only constant in life, Frank.
之前的假期我们没来过巴黎
We didn't come to Paris on vacation.
哦 在巴黎我想你能做的就是
Oh. Shopping's what I thought you did in Paris
花男朋友的票子去购物来作为补偿
with your boyfriend's money
当他被衣衫不整的 放荡的
while you're waiting for him
俄国贱前女友迷晕放倒
to wake up from being taken down
你还得辛苦的等着他醒过来
by his skanky, slutty, Russian biatch ex-girlfriend.
感谢 感谢你赞美我这件皮草
So thanks. Thanks. Thanks for the compliment for the fur.
因为你说我穿这件裙子很美 我感觉相当好
For telling me that I look nice in my dress. It makes me feel really good.
这样也让我感觉好有爱
And it makes me feel very loving towards you also.
她为什么要这么对我?
Why is she doing this to me?
我们打的过去吧
We can get a taxi over here.
弗兰克 听着 我跟你说些事
Frank, listen, I gotta tell you something.
你要学会分享你的感受 来挽回这段感情
You have to start to learn to share your feelings to evolve your relationship.
尽管做到这点一开始会很不适应
Even if it seems uncomfortable at first.
就说你身处枪林弹雨中
Say you're pinned down in a firefight.
如果你原地不动 你就会没命 行吗?
If you stay where you are, you're gonna die. Okay?
现在你告诉我 你要怎么做?
So, you tell me, what do you do?
行动起来
Make the run.
对 你必须行动直到感觉安全了
Yes. You have got to make the run to emotional safety.
啊
Huh.
摩西 你死了没?
You dead yet, Moses?
还没
Not yet.
我的飞机呢?
Where's my plane?
在我菊花里!
In my ass!
- 在巴黎外郊飞机场那  - 你到底...闭嘴!
- It's in an airport outside of Paris.  - What are you... Shut up!
快离开这
Let's get outta here.
- 马文?  - 嗯?
- Marvin?  - Yeah?
你口袋里是不是还有一颗炸弹?
Is that a stick of dynamite in your pocket?
是啊 我留着它是为了以防万一
Yeah, but I'm saving it for an emergency.
那 现在不就是万一的紧急时刻了吗?
Well, this is kind of an emergency, isn't it?
我给她的那把钥匙与一个极其猖獗的恐怖组织有关
The key I gave her is connected to a particularly nasty terrorist cell
就是他们保险柜的钥匙
and their safe deposit box.
法国人解决这类事很完美啊
The French take this kinda thing pretty seriously.
够了
That's enough.
放开我! 立即放开我!
Put me down! Put me down now!
好吧
All right.
我们得快走了 莫斯科会在一小时内放了她
We gotta move quickly, Moscow will have her out within the hour.
再见了美国情人
For the love of Mike.
是的
All right.
我没和你说话
I'm still not talking to you.
这是一份关于龙葵的军情六处报告
All right. This is an MI6 report on Project Nightshade.
是关于安置核装置的那个特工
It's about the operative that placed the device.
他们拘留并把他处以ICE
They took him into custody and put him on ICE.
什么是ICE?
What's ICE?
监禁但不能处死 他们会把谁留在ICE长达三十二年呢?
Incarcerate, Cannot Execute. Who would they keep on ICE for 32 years?
- 快 得走了  - 去哪? 哦!
- Come on. Gotta go.  - Come on where? Oh!
她怎么会发现我们?
How could she have possibly found us?
因为我打电话告诉她我们要来
Cause I called her and told her we were coming.
与其被偷偷干掉 不如面对面比较好
I couldn't take the pressure of not knowing.
为什么她还不开枪?
Why isn't she shooting at us?
这样能使我们省下二十四小时
That should buy us 24 hours.
你好 亲爱的
Hello, sweetie.
下次你俩再制定这样一个计划时
You know, the next time you two make a plan like this,
最起码要让我参与进来
you could at least let me in on it.
弗兰克 你在怀疑我的判断力
Frank, you're compromising me.
鬼知道你会不会昏了头告诉那女人?
Who knows what some girl is gonna squeeze out of you?
你从哪找的这些尸体?
Where'd you get the bodies?
我的冰箱里
My freezer.
快起来
Come on. Wake up.
喂?
Yeah?
事办的怎样了?
What the hell's going on?
- 长官?  - 从青蛙那得到什么了吗?
- Sir?  - Get anything from The Frog?
还没 在我们谈之前他服了种毒
No, he took some sorta poison before we really talked.
我觉得他现在什么都说不出来
I don't think he's gonna say anything now.
你必须找到摩西和博格斯
You've got to find Moses and Boggs.
嗯 嗯
Mmm. Mmm.
别担心 我在追踪
Don't worry. I'm on the trail.
在你的右边 能欣赏到著名的伦敦塔
On your right, you see the famous Tower of London.
很快 我们将在伦敦桥下穿过
And shortly, we'll be passing under the Tower Bridge.
这是个城堡
It's a fortress.
这是所专收精神病罪犯的精神病院 他在ICE间
It's an asylum for the criminally insane. He's in the ICE unit.
那是被军情六处深埋在地下的最高安全设施
That's an MI6 Alpha Level secure facility buried deep within that building.
就像是一所监狱中的监狱
It's like a prison within a prison.
那我们怎么到那?
How are we gonna get in there?
她想要我的头! 她想要我的头! 这是个天主教徒的阴谋
She wants my head! She wants my head! It's a Papist plot.
是她 就是玛丽那个贱人 苏格兰女王 她想要我的头
It's her. It's that bitch Mary, Queen of Scots. She wants my head.
你们在干什么? 放开我! 放开我!
What are you doing? No! No!
把塞西尔带来 把塞西尔带来 我才是英国女王
Get me Cecil. Get me Cecil. I'm the Queen of England!
不要把我带到塔里! 你个贱人 我要砍你的头!
Don't take me to the Tower! I'll have your head for this, you bitch!
不! 不!
No! No!
"为王者无安宁"
"Uneasy lies the head that wears the crown."
他们都在谋害我
They're plotting against me. All of them.
这才是好女王
There's a good queen.
够了 老疯子
Stuff it, you old bat.
谢谢你
Thank you.
如果你不介意的话 还不是很"老"
Not so much the "old," if you don't mind.
我觉得我演的超好
I think it was really, really good.
我都有点与贝蒂·戴维斯通灵了
I thought I was kind of channeling Bette Davis.
早上好 琼斯医生要去见十七号囚犯
Good morning. Dr. Jones to see prisoner number 17, please.
琼斯医生? 你是军情六处的吗?
Dr. Jones? Are you with MI6?
很遗憾 不再是了
Sadly, not anymore.
因为我没在名单上找到你
Because I don't seem to have you on my list.
该死的这没用啊 为什么?
Bloody thing's not working. Why's that?
你应该用...
You're supposed to use...
趴在地上
Lay down on the ground.
好样的 趴在地上
Attaboy. On the floor.
一百二十一号 在这
Number 121. Oh, there it is.
弗兰克!
Frank!
你们是谁? 是客人吗? 你们在找谁?
Who are you? You're visitors? Who are you looking for?
我们喜欢有客人来 不是吗? 老兄们
We love having visitors, don't we, fellas?
白利博士?
Dr. Bailey?
你想找谁? 嗯?
Yes. Who did you expect to find here? Hmm?
- 先生...  - 什么?
- Sir...  - What?
我看见你死了
I saw you die.
看见我死了? 他是谁?
Saw me die? Who is he?
弗兰克?
Frank?
弗兰克·摩西 我亲爱的老兄!
Frank Moses, my dear fellow!
你好吗 老兄? 真高兴能见到你 真高兴你能来
How are you, old sport? So glad to see you. So glad you came by.
我们一直在等你 不是吗 伙计们?
We've been expecting you. Haven't we, fellas?
天呐 弗兰克 你怎么这么老了 天呐!
My God, Frank, why are you so old? Good lord!
- 先生...  - 怎么了?
- Sir...  - What?
你已经被关在这三十二年了
You've been locked up here for 32 years.
得了吧 弗兰克 你是在逗我吧
Come on, Frankie, you've gotta be kidding me.
快 练练手
Come on, put 'em up.
三十二年 多离奇啊 你是谁?
Thirty-two years. How extraordinary. Who are you?
维多利亚
Victoria.
维多利亚! 你应该读读这个
Victoria! You should read this.
列宁的国家与革命 美好的时光 都怪斯大林乱搞
Lenin. State and Revolution. Jolly good time. Stalin got it wrong, of course.
弗兰克 我们要去哪? 你今晚要带我们去剧院吗?
So where are we going, Frank? Are you taking us
弗兰克 那是我们今晚要去的地方吗?
to the opera again tonight? Is that where we're going, Frank?
剧院? 我们喜欢歌剧 不是吗? 伙计们
The opera? We love the opera, don't we, fellas?
是的 有歌剧 香槟和草莓
Yes, the opera and the champagne and the strawberries all round.
抱歉 亲爱的 你叫什么来着?
Sorry, my dear, what is your name again?
维多利亚
Victoria.
不好意思 这是他们一直给我
I'm sorry, it's the drugs
吃的药害的 我只有短期记忆
they've been feeding me, it's my short-term memory.
他们给我吃的药...
The drugs they've been feeding...
应该是想让我们安静下来
Something that's meant to keep us peaceful, I suppose,
或让我们不添麻烦!
or harmless!
总之 我知道就在这附近
Anyway, I know it's around here somewhere,
但我不知道具体在哪
but I don't know where it is.
白利博士 我们需要你的帮助
Dr. Bailey, we need your help.
- 什么?  - 你记得龙葵吗?
- Mmm?  - Do you remember Nightshade?
抱歉 我在找我的烟斗还有圣克里斯托弗像章
I'm sorry, I'm looking for my pipe and my St. Christopher medallion.
孩子们总是乱拿东西送人
Boys gave it to someone.
他们是小男孩
They were little boys, you see.
现在它去哪了... 不知怎么地不见了
Now where it's gone... It's gone somehow.
啊...
Um...
妈的!
Oh, shit!
嘿 弗兰克 我在这
Hey, Frankie, I'm over here.
我找到像章了 它一直在我兜里
I found it. it was in my pocket the whole time.
我还是找不到我那该死的烟斗 但像章在这
I couldn't find my damn pipe, though. But here it is.
抱歉 亲爱的 你刚问我什么问题来着?
Sorry, my dear, what was the question you asked me?
你记得龙葵吗?
Do you remember Nightshade?
模糊记得 是一种炸弹吧
Vaguely. It was some kind of a bomb, I believe.
白利博士 人们在寻找那个武器
Dr. Bailey, people are looking for that weapon.
人们想要使用它
People who want to use it.
哦 天呐 是的 我当然知道 相信我
Oh, dear. Yes, I do understand, of course. Believe you me.
知道吗 我为美国人做了很多
But you know, I made many things for the Americans and
但最后龙葵可以说是一场噩梦
Nightshade turned out to be a bit of a nightmare.
太不一样了 最终证明是太危险了
It was quite different. Turned out to be too dangerous.
所以自然地 他们就把我关在这个地方了
So naturally, they had to lock me up in this place.
之后我觉得他们对我做的这些相当正常
And after what they did to me, I think it's perfectly natural
我让他们所有的人都滚!
I tell them all to go F off!
军情六处企图伪造白利的死? 为什么啊? 他们在隐藏什么?
MI6 tried to fake Bailey's death? Why? What are they hiding?
你得走了 你得查查了
You're gonna have to go. You're gonna have to go find out.
你知道他们将会审讯然后杀了我的
You know they're gonna try and kill me.
- 我在俄罗斯给你打电话  - 再见
- I'll call you from Russia.  - Do svidanya.
注意七号通道
Maintenance to Bridge 7.
最高安全区域被入侵
We got a breach in Maximum Security.
抓住她!
Secure!
什么事这么重要?
All right, what's so important?
我刚从军情六处得到消息说爱德华·白利还活着而且逃跑了
I just heard from my source at MI6 that Edward Bailey's alive and on the run.
- 这不可能啊  - 这比一个桀骜不驯的将军
- That's not possible.  - This is bigger than a rogue general
和他的未爆炸武器的事更大 还有什么我不知道的?
and his unexploded ordnance. What don't I know?
游戏已经变味了
The game has changed.
白利知道的对我们来说太危险了
The things Bailey knows are too dangerous.
我们不能让白利或龙葵落入恐怖分子手中 否则数百万的人将会死
We can't let Bailey or Nightshade fall into terrorist hands, or millions will die.
见鬼 这是真的
Holy shit, it's real.
如果不采取措施 核武器将在莫斯科市中心爆炸
Unless we secure it, that weapon's going off in the middle of Moscow.
现在来看 那算是最好的情况了
Right now, that's our best case scenario.
伙计们?
Guys?
啊!
Ah!
欢迎你们 我的朋友
Welcome, my friends.
你真的还活着
So, it is true. You're alive.
告诉我那东西在哪?
Tell me, then, where is this device?
谁?
Who?
还在进行中
Work in progress.
我从没想过能把
I never thought I'd be smuggling
弗兰克·摩西偷带进俄罗斯
Frank Moses into the heart of Mother Russia.
我也是
Me, neither.
在我没忘之前 弗兰克 有点小事
Oh, before I forget. Frank. Frank, a little something.
如果你被抓了或韩追上你了
If you are caught or Han catches you,
还是服毒自尽比较好
suicide pill is a much better option than what you face.
面带俄罗斯式微笑死去
You die with Russian smile on.
祝你好运 再见
Good luck. Do svidanya.
- 白利先生  - 怎么了 弗兰克
- Mr. Bailey.  - Yes, Frank?
你能告诉我们核武器藏在哪里吗?
Is there any way you could tell us where you hid the nuclear weapon?
弗兰克 看这些奶牛 它们多美啊
Look at all those cows, Frank. They're beautiful.
是啊
Yeah.
奶牛?
Cows?
嗨! 喂!
Hi! Yoo hoo!
情况不妙
That's not good.
弗兰克 我们被盯上了
We have eyes on, Frank.
我的飞机呢?
Where's my plane?
他们雇我杀你
They paid me to kill you.
他们没说让我一次就解决掉
They didn't say I had to do it all at once.
摩西 这事没完
This is not over, Moses.
我们没完! 没完!
We're not over! It's not!
他怎么了?
What's wrong with him?
哇
Wow.
这是哪?
What is this place?
我第一个藏身之处
My first safe house.
自从一九八四年就未动过 哇!
Untouched, since 1984. Aw!
这是河豚毒?
Fugu poison?
河豚毒是致命的东西 死的很惨
Fugu poison is deadly stuff. Terrible death.
这是你要的那玩意儿吗? XKG毒气 我发明的
This your little gizmo? XKG gas. I invented it.
我们企图除掉老菲德尔·卡斯特罗
We tried to take out old Fidel Castro in 61 in Cuba.
但还是没能成功
That didn't work though.
弗兰克 来点茶吗?
Any tea, Frank?
为什么韩这么恨你?
Why does Han hate you so much?
他小时候缺乏关爱
Not enough hugs as a child.
弗兰克陷害他窃取国家机密
Frank framed him for stealing state secrets.
所以他从一位高端反情报官员
So he went from being a highly decorated counter-intel officer
变成了个贱民
to... to being a pariah.
更讽刺的是 弗兰克给自己的生命
What's ironic though, is that Frank actually created the circumstances
创造了一个巨大的威胁
for his own death.
太富有诗意了
It's poetic.
我还不是没死吗
I ain't dead yet.
那能吃吗?
Should you eat that?
吃下去安全吗?
Is that safe?
按这上面的保质期来看 还没过期呢
It's before they had that, you know, "sell by" date stuff.
哦
Oh.
你见过卡斯特罗?
So did you get to meet Castro?
谁?
Who?
你见过卡斯特罗吗?
Did you get to meet Castro?
见过 在肯尼迪被暗杀的两周后
Yes, I did, actually. About two weeks after Kennedy was assassinated.
说起这个 弗兰克
Talking of which, Frank,
我慢慢想起自己是谁了
I'm starting to remember more and more who I am
做过些什么 以及我制造的武器
and who I was and the weapons I made.
天呐 真是奇迹
My God, it really is amazing.
军情六处的家伙们真是有效率 上帝保佑他们...
How efficiently those boys from MI6, may God bless 'em...
就是这样 弗兰克
But you know something, Frank?
一旦发现留着我们没用了
They really do throw us away. Don't they, old sport?
就立即把我们处理了 不是吗? 老兄
When we're no longer convenient, I suppose.
完全不在乎我们把最好的年华献给了他们
As though we'd never given them the best years of our lives.
开个玩笑
Bit of a joke, really.
是的 异常奇怪
Yes, very strange.
你记得龙葵在哪吗?
Do you remember where Nightshade is?
能再说一遍吗?
I'm sorry, my dear?
你记得龙葵在哪吗?
Do you remember where Nightshade is?
记得
Oh, yes.
现在这儿应该对了
Now, this feels right.
就在这附近 这次我确信
It's around here somewhere. I'm sure this time.
一切都和以前完全不一样了
Everything looks different completely.
也许就在那
Maybe it's over here.
- 都找了好几个小时了  - 对 就是这儿
- It's been hours. Hours.  - Yeah, this is it.
到了
Here we are.
穿着吉米·丘跑路舒服吗?(著名奢侈品牌女鞋)
How are those Jimmy Choos working out for you?
入口在这儿
The entrance is up there.
谁是棒约翰?
Who's Papa John?
这是新开的
It's new.
到哪里的入口?
Entrance to what?
通向老王宫的秘密通道
Secret tunnels through the old catacombs.
勃列日涅夫当年用来与情妇幽会
Brezhnev used it to sneak his mistress in.
- 在哪?  - 就在这
- In where?  - In there.
克里姆林宫?
The Kremlin?
武器在克里姆林宫?
The weapon is in the Kremlin?
这是他们绝对想不到的地方
It's the one place they wouldn't look.
天呐 记着要保温啊?
Jesus. Do you mind keeping it warm?
知道你造成了多大的损失吗
You have no idea the damage you've done.
你把我们自己人关了三十二年
You kept one of our own locked up for 32 years.
我维护了世界安全
I have kept the world safe.
- 如果那个武器落入坏人之手...  - 武器?
- If that weapon falls into the wrong hands...  - The weapon?
你根本什么都不知道
You haven't the slightest idea.
你得让我打给摩西
You must let me call Moses.
他不知道自己将面对什么
He doesn't know what he's walking into.
你曾经有过机会 现在没了
You've had your chance. It's over.
抱歉 维多利亚
I'm sorry, Victoria.
抱歉个屁
Sorry, my ass.
他们说你是这里的传奇人物
They say you're a legend around here.
我...
I've...
我从来都没听说过你
I've never heard of you.
肯定是在我来之前
Must have been a bit before my time.
好了 你现在见识过了
Well, you've heard of me now.
他们怎么可能从没发现炸弹产生的辐射?
How is it possible they never picked up the radiation signature from that bomb?
这问题问得好
That's the million dollar question.
伙计 这是新的
Hey, gang. This is new.
你觉得这堵墙后有什么?
What do you think is behind that wall?
呃...
Um...
我认为是俄国人
I think Russians.
如果那个洞被人发现 我们就死定了
If anybody sees that hole, we're dead.
我需要你帮忙拆除炸弹
I'm gonna need you to help me to disarm the weapon.
弗兰克 总得有人看着门
Frank, somebody's gotta guard the door.
- 不行  - 但是...
- No.  - But...
你需要这个
You'll need this.
将军同志
这是二十分钟前在红场拍到的
搜索建筑 派部队支援
再说一遍
One more time.
很好 很好 意思是什么?
Great. Great. What does that mean?
"煤气泄漏 等待维修"
"Gas leak. Maintenance is coming."
- 好的 然后他们就会走开  - 如果他们没走呢?
- Good. And then they'll move on.  - And what if they don't?
- 要枪吗?  - 要
- Want a gun?  - Yes.
不行 不要枪
No. No gun.
不能动 你是保安
Just don't move. You're a security guard.
不许笑 你不能笑
Don't smile. You can't smile.
你别离开你的岗位 好吗?
You just never leave your post. Okay?
很好
Nice.
两枪 打这儿和这儿
Two shots, here and here.
把尸体拖进去 有必要的话就多杀几个
Drag the body in there and repeat as necessary.
- 枪没保险  - 没有
- No safety.  - No safety.
弗兰克 我不喜欢克林姆林宫
Frank, I don't like the Kremlin so much.
我更不喜欢在它的下面
And I like being underneath it even less.
我们到了
Here we are.
太棒了 恍如昨日
That's great. It's just like yesterday.
这是我的扳手也可以说是撬杆 看这个
There's my wrench or crow bar. Look at this.
那里
There.
嘿 看 伙计们
Hey, look, chaps.
这是我的旧烟斗 我就知道我把它落在哪里了
That's my old pipe. I knew I'd left it somewhere.
我爱妻买的第五个 那是一九六九年
My dear wife bought this the fifth, 1969.
这是我们的结婚纪念品 噢 对了! 这个 呃...
It was our wedding anniversary. Oh, yes! This is, um...
顺便说下 这就是龙葵
This is Nightshade, by the way.
看那
There.
- 那是...  - 红汞核弹
- Is that...  - That's Red Mercury.
红汞?
Red Mercury?
人们都说它只存在于冷战神话中
We were always told it was a Cold War myth.
是 他们都说这不可能 但是我做到了 看到没?
Yes, they said it couldn't be done, but I did it. See?
弗兰克 如果它是红汞核弹 那你可以把它装进包里
Frank, if that's Red Mercury, you can zip it up in a backpack
在白宫巡游 没人会发现
and take it on the White House tour. It's undetectable.
没有信号 没有辐射
No signature. No fallout.
这个武器将会在一夜之间完全改变
This is a weapon that will entirely change
国际力量的平衡 像那样
the balance of international power overnight. Just like that.
我们都会死
We're all gonna die.
跪下
On your knees.
卡塔亚
Katja.
任何政府都不能占有这个武器
No government should have this weapon.
你的国家不行 我的也不行
Not yours. And not mine.
我有命令在身
I have orders.
这与命令无关 这关乎是非
This isn't about orders. This is about right and wrong.
不要逼我
Don't.
你真的有来美国看我?
Did you really come to see me in the States?
是
Yes.
那时 我房子外的花是什么颜色的?
What color were the flowers outside my house?
黄色
Yellow.
我发现你一直站在这里啊
煤气泄漏 等待维修
我叫帕沙 回头一起喝一杯吧
好?
我想你也注意到我了?
搞什么... 嘿!
What in the name of... Hey!
你亲这个人干嘛啊?
What are you doing kissing this guy?
我不想杀他
I didn't wanna kill him.
这是什么狗屁逻辑?
What kinda stupid logic is that?
她来这干什么啊?
What in the Sam Hill is she doing here?
她又和我们合作了
She's working with us again.
那才见鬼呢
Like heck she is.
你干嘛亲他?
Why were you kissing that guy?
伙计们 在克林姆林宫发生的就让它过去吧
Kids, what happens in the Kremlin stays in the Kremlin.
你要和我好好解释这事
You are gonna have to explain this to me.
同志们!
Hey, Comrades!
为了更多的成功
Here's to more success.
成功
Success.
还有拯救世界!
And saving the world!
拯救世界!
Saving the world!
干杯!
Na zdorovie!
我接个电话 马上回来
I got this. Right back.
嘿
Hey.
你在哪?
Where are you?
莫斯科
Moscow.
他是个疯子 弗兰克
He's a nutter, Francis.
军情六处把他关起来不是因为他制造了那武器
MI6 didn't lock him up because he created the weapon
而是因为他想引爆武器
but because he wants to see it go off.
嗨 弗兰克
Hello, Frank.
那是维多利亚 是吧?
That was Victoria, wasn't it?
她和你说我是个怪物
Telling you that I was some sort of a monster
曾经想毁灭苏联帝国
who once wanted to destroy the Soviet empire.
好 慢慢转过身
Yeah. Very slowly.
没错 好孩子
That's it. Good boy.
很好 进去
Good. In you go.
马文...
Marvin...
放下枪
Guns down.
放下武器 慢慢来
Weapons down. Very slowly.
你故意把它透露给维基解密
You planted the thing on WikiLeaks.
是的 我从守卫那拿了个手机
Oh, yes, it was a cell phone taken from a guard.
我只是渴望能够报复军情六处
I was just itching to get my revenge on MI6, you see.
弗兰克 你找到青蛙太不可思议了
Frank, you were absolutely marvelous the way you found The Frog.
其他人绝对找不到他
No one else could have found him.
杰克?
Jack?
对不起 弗兰克 我已经拿红汞和霍顿先生做了交易
Sorry, Frank, I made a deal already with Mr. Horton for Red Mercury.
- 干得好 白利  - 谢谢
- Well done, Bailey.  - Thanks.
很高兴又见到你 弗兰克 把枪都捡起来
Nice to see you again, Frank. Pick up the guns.
祖国不会忘记你 弗兰克
Your country appreciates your sacrifice, Frank.
但你们的时代过去了
But your time's up.
我们走
Let's go.
是时候了 白利
It's time, Bailey.
是的 没错
Yes, it is time.
多有趣啊
Very Interesting.
叛逃的美国特工变身为核恐怖分子 杀害了俄罗斯高官
Rogue American agents turned nuclear terrorists kill top Russian officer.
不妙啊
Not good.
永别了 弗兰克 永别了 马文
So long, Frank. So long, Marvin.
来吧 伙计们 走吧
Come on, boys, let's go.
放松 放松
Easy. Easy.
让我帮你拿吧
Oh, please, let me take that from you.
我以为我们要去伦敦做任务汇报
I thought we were doing the debriefing in London.
本来是要去的 但既然你是这么个病态而又心理扭曲的混蛋
Oh, we were. But since you're such a sick, twisted bastard,
你要去科罗拉多
you're going to Colorado.
那里有一个秘密的设施 在地下一英里处
There's a secret facility there, it's about a mile underground,
你要在那里度过余生 你大脑的所有认知
where you will spend your remaining years having every bit of knowledge
都会被清除
plucked from that giant head of yours.
真的吗?
Really? Hmm.
既然我们都摊开说了
And since we're speaking frankly,
我就告诉你吧 那里会你会觉得之前被关的32年
I should say that it will make your last 32 years
像是在加勒比海度假
seem like a vacation in the Caribbean.
给他铐上
Cuff him.
嗯
Mmm.
我说吧
Oh, I say.
好吧
Well, well.
你没想到吧 老头?
Bet you didn't see that coming. Did you, old man?
我必须说 我真没想到 太好了
I must say, I didn't. Jolly good.
你先请
After you.
谢谢 早上好 先生们
Thank you. Good morning, gentlemen.
他说什么?
What did he say?
预备
Ready.
做点什么啊
Do something. Do something.
我爱你
I love you.
至少不是韩先抓到我们
At least Han didn't get us first.
不是吧? 这种时候你还提他干嘛?
Really? You're gonna bring that up right now?
啊 世界上再也没有什么比一个美丽的女人拿帅气的枪
Ah, there is nothing more sexy in the whole world
更性感的了
than a beautiful woman with an incredible gun.
你真是个浪漫派
You're such a romantic.
小心
Watch your eyes.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
我喜欢开枪前你的脚趾这样弯起
I love the way your toes curl right before you fire.
无药可救
Hopeless.
嗯
Mmm.
哇!
Ah!
- 不许动  - 嘘!
- Freeze.  - Shh!
你知道吗? 我觉得你没必要拿枪指着我
You know something? I don't think you ought to point that idiotic thing at me.
你该好好想想自己签的安保协议是否包括丧葬费?
You should really start thinking about your security protocol, don't you think?
那是什么东西?
What the hell is that?
那个 孩子 是解毒剂
That, my dear boy, is an antidote
世上最强神经毒气的解毒剂 看
to the most powerful nerve agent ever created. Look.
伙计们 你们好啊
Hello, boys.
戴维斯先生 你好啊
Hello, Mr. Davis.
你没料到吧
And you didn't see that coming.
有想到吗 老伙计?
Did you, old sport?
我确定你不想错过接下来的精彩内容
I'm sure you wouldn't want to miss what's coming next.
这是一点点解药 很好
It's a little antidote. Jolly good.
好了
That's right.
啊
Uh, uh, uh, uh.
很好 谢谢
Good. Thank you.
太好了
Jolly good.
老实说 两天 弗兰克 才两天
Honestly, two days, Frank, two days,
你就落到行刑队手里了?
and you're in front of a firing squad?
是 但是你看...
Yeah. But look...
不用 不要解释 你明明可以做得更好 太可悲了
No. No excuses. You're better than this. It's pathetic.
弗兰克 一架美国军用飞机在伦敦紧急降落
Frank, an American military transport made an emergency landing in London.
飞机上所有人都死了
Everyone aboard was found dead.
白利已经到伊朗使馆避难
Bailey has taken refuge in the Iranian embassy.
伊朗使馆?
The Iranian embassy?
我们要去那里
We've gotta go there.
好的 让他们准备好
All right. Get 'em ready.
我去确保下我们能起飞
I'm gonna make sure we're cleared for takeoff.
如果世界就在一周内灭亡
If the world is here in a week,
咱们在特克斯和凯科斯群岛见
I will meet you in the Turks and Caicos.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
我们整个晚上
And we will spend all night
- 都在星空下度过  - 都在星空下度过
- beneath the stars.  - Beneath the stars.
嗯...
Mmm...
我不说韩语!
I don't speak Korean!
你玩得开心吗?
You having fun yet?
我开始觉得开心时会告诉你
I'll let you know when I start having fun.
你背叛了我
You betrayed me.
我别无选择
I had no choice.
如果换作是你 你也会这么做的
You'd have done the same thing, if you were me.
美国付你多少钱?
How much is the US paying you?
两千万
20 million.
你和我开玩笑呢?
Are you kiddin' me?
我要得更多
I asked for more.
你怎么了?
What happened to you?
你以前是个好探员
You used to be a good agent.
停! 等等 听着 我需要你的帮助
Stop! Wait a minute. Listen, I need your help.
我知道你内心还是想做正确的事情
I know there's a part of you that wants to do the right thing.
有一个武器将会被引爆...
There is a weapon that's gonna be detonated...
胡扯
Bullshit.
不是胡扯
It's not bullshit.
有个炸弹正在前往伦敦
There's a bomb headed for London right now.
如果你不帮我的话 一百一十万的人将会失去生命
Eleven million people are gonna lose their lives if you don't help me.
好吧
All right.
我们走
Let's go.
我可没说以后不杀你
This doesn't mean I'm not going to kill you later.
我知道
I know.
我觉得要让恋爱顺利
I think the way to make a relationship work
你们两个都不能放弃自我 你同意吗 马文?
is that neither of you give up who you are. Don't you agree, Marvin?
精彩 马文说得太好了
Exactly. Exactly what Marvin says.
相爱就像跳崖 你只需要信任并放手
Falling in love is like jumping off a cliff. You just have to believe and let go.
天啊!
My God!
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
没事 他没问题
No, he's all right.
他是和我们一起的
He's with us.
我们谈开了
We talked it out.
杀了白利 拿到武器
Kill Bailey. Secure the weapon.
这会有多难呢?
How hard can it be?
当然 外围的安保非常森严
Of course, the external security is very, very heavy
里面是革命护卫队的核心部分
but inside there are hardcore Revolutionary Guards.
他们都是极端的狂热者
They are serious fanatics.
成败都取决于她
The whole thing depends on her.
你确实知道 如果他们抓到你 他们会杀了你吧
You do realize, if they catch you, they will kill you.
伦敦
我知道这个对你来说不容易 但是别担心
I know this won't be easy for you, but don't worry.
好吗?
Okay?
你要知道 我一直都在想
You know, I've been thinking about
你和我
you and me.
还有我只是...
And I just...
送你一样东西
I got you something.
喔
Wow.
喜欢吗?
You like it?
- 太喜欢了  - 七连发哦
- I love it.  - Seven rounds.
- 好吧  - 还不到时候 我还没准备好
- Okay.  - Not yet. I'm not ready.
停 不 现在还不行 等一下吧
Stop, no. Not right now. Wait.
如果现在不做 你就把这事搞砸了 知道吗?
If you don't do it, you're gonna blow it, all right?
看着我
Look at me.
- 我数到三  - 嗯 听着...
- I'm gonna count to three.  - Mmm. Listen...
我数到三 好吗?
I'm gonna count to three, okay?
- 我们还能回去...  - 我用英语数
- We can go back to the...  - In English.
- 一...  - 别现在 不 等下
- One...  - Not now. No. Wait.
二...
Two...
该死
God damn it.
嗨
Hi.
她会被杀死的
She's gonna get killed.
这帮人离开老巢之后会很小心的
It's tough when they leave the nest.
弗兰克 想想吧 不管你信不信
Frank, come on. A little trust.
她有你我都不具备的天赋
She has talents you and I will never have.
什么天赋?
What talents?
人见人爱
People like her.
如果她能活下来 这对你们的关系很有帮助
If she lives, this'll be good for your relationship.
说得对
You're right.
我自认唯一了解的事物 就是女人和秘密行动
And if there's one thing I know, it's women and covert ops.
这是两件事啊
That's two things.
不 蠢蛋
No, grasshopper.
这是一回事
It is not.
我想告诉你一个秘密 部长先生
I wanna tell you a secret, Mr. Minister.
她还想跟这家伙亲热?
Is she gonna make out with this guy, too?
哦!
Ohh!
你搞什么鬼?
What the hell was that?
河豚毒
Blowfish poison.
你的身体马上会感觉到麻痹感和枪伤的疼痛
Paralysis and shooting pains will grip your entire body.
你会慢慢的窒息而死
And you will slowly asphyxiate until you choke to death
整个过程意识清醒 除非你照我说得做
while remaining fully-conscious, unless you do exactly what I say.
来不及叛国我就会死的
I will die before I compromise my country.
好的 我们带你去你的办公室 你要用官方信纸写一封文书来
Okay. We will drive you to your office where you will write a letter on official stationery
谴责伊朗妇女所受的虐待
denouncing the treatment of women in Iran.
然后你就能拿到解药
Then you will get your antidote.
就这些?
That's it?
伦敦 伊朗大使馆
有什么可以效劳的?
How may I help you?
我想投靠伊朗
啊 白利博士 不好意思推迟了时间
Ah. Dr. Bailey, my apologies for the delay.
邓布洛维斯基教授已经表明了这个武器是真的
Professor Dombrovski has declared the weapon authentic.
而且我们已经准备好发射了
And we're prepared to proceed.
只要我能拿到钱就行 大使先生
As soon as my money's transferred, Mr. Ambassador.
闪开! 她和我一起的
Move! She's with me.
阿曼?
Arman?
你得让他走
He needs to go.
好的 好的
Okay, okay.
你们说什么呢? 她是谁?
What are you talking about? Who is she?
先生 实在抱歉 你得离开这
Sir, I'm sorry, you need to leave.
你给我闭嘴!
You need to shut up!
不
No.
你们到底在这干什么呢?
What? What is happening here?
抱歉 你在干吗?
Sorry. What are you doing?
告诉我 你们在这干什么! 她是谁?
Tell me what is happening here! Who is she?
滚出去! 我说"滚出去"的时候 你就给我滚出去!
Get out! When I say "get out," get out of here!
你得离开这!
You need to go!
你他妈给我闭嘴!
You shut the fuck up!
保险柜在哪?
Where's the safe?
什么?
What?
保险柜在哪?
Where's the safe?
便便来咯
Poo poo's coming.
24小时服务
24 Hour Plumbing.
快 紧急情况 到处都是水 快来
Hurry. Emergency. Water everywhere. Come quick.
停下! 水管工 等一下!
Stop! Plumbers, wait!
没事! 这边走
It's okay! This way.
钱到了
Money received.
干得好
Good show.
来见见我们的朋友吧
Let's see our friend here.
能借我下你的刀子吗?
Would you lend me your knife, please?
多谢
Thank you.
不好意思弄脏了地毯
Sorry about the mess on the carpet.
哦对了
Oh, well.
这会儿 杰克... 希望你不介意我这么叫你
At this point, Jack... You don't mind me calling you "Jack," I hope.
你一定开始意识到
You must be beginning to comprehend
你是彻彻底底的失败了
the stunning totality of your failure.
你不能把它给他们
You can't give it to them.
哦 比起我把红汞给他们
Oh, I've no more interest in giving Red Mercury
我更想给你
to these boys than I have in giving it to you.
天哪
Jesus.
是啊 我们还是在悲哀的旧世界
Yes, it's a sad old world, you know.
不管怎么样 我是这么想的
Anyway, that's only my opinion.
但是关键的是 杰克
But the central point is this, Jack,
你看 像你啊 或者军情六处 或者中情局的这些混蛋
you see, when men like you and those dickheads from MI6
不管你们从哪个部门来的
or CIA or whatever sewers you came from.
当你们不仅要杀我
When you take away not only my life
还要杀我深爱但无辜的妻子娜塔莎
but the innocent lives of my dear beloved wife Natasha
还要杀我六岁的小儿子的时候 看看吧 是啊
and my little boy, who was only six, you see. Yes.
我还能说什么?
I mean, what can I say?
你们既然惹了我 老弟
When you mess with me, buddy,
这就是你的下场
this is what you get.
见鬼去吧 老不死的
Go to hell, old man.
再见吧 爱国英雄
Fare thee well, patriot.
砰
Boom.
下一步该什么了?
Now what's next?
啊 华盛顿
Ah, Washington.
宝贝 嘿
Baby, hey.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
哈!
Hah!
牛!
Awesome!
哦 妈的
Oh, shit.
- 就那个玩意儿?  - 正在倒计时 弗兰克
- Is that it?  - It's counting down, Frank.
关掉它 好吗?
Shut it Off. Right?
关... 好啊 怎么关? 声控啊?
Shut... Yeah. With what? Acupressure?
- 我不知道  - 那为啥让我干呢?
- I don't know.  - Well, why is it my responsibility?
快做点什么吧
Just do something.
就凭我的破化学?
With my Mr. Chemistry set?
我不知道该怎么做 你想让我去按按钮?
I don't know what I'm doing. You want me to push a button?
白利跑了 炸弹开始计时了
Bailey's loose and the bomb's ticking.
等一下 劳驾女士
Wait. Excuse me, ma'am.
你好 我有个约会
Hello, I have an appointment.
枪!
Gun!
把炸弹拿走
Get that bomb outta here.
- 把它扔下 亲爱的 没错  - 我的枪!
- Drop it now, darling. That's right.  - My gun!
按下按钮 下楼
Press the button. Ground floor.
马文 快走!
Marvin, let's go!
干得真漂亮
Jolly good show.
妈的
Bollocks.
你真要开这破玩意儿?
You really drive this ridiculous thing?
你能射击吗?
Can you shoot?
你得引导我们一下 弗兰克
We need eyes, Francis.
来吧 弗兰克 我们还有四十分钟
Come on, Frank. Forty minutes.
马文 你在后面干得怎么样?
Marvin, how ya doin' back there?
我现在不能和你说话
I can't talk to you right now.
伤口如何?
How is it?
没什么事
It's fine.
妈的!
Shit!
给我秀一下
Show me something.
维多利亚
Victoria,
我正在观察 白利要上M4号高速公路
I got eyes on. Bailey's heading for the M4.
收到
Got it.
搞定!
Got it!
这条线可能会止爆 这一条可能会引爆
This one should stop it and this one should detonate it.
各百分之五十的几率 弗兰克
It's fifty-fifty, Frank.
等下!
Wait!
不对头啊
That's weird.
你知道你在干什么吗?
Do you have any idea what you're doing?
等下 等等! 等等!
Wait, wait! Wait!
别剪了!
Stop cutting wires!
我早知道我们要死了!
I knew we were gonna die!
- 准备好干掉这个狗娘养的了吗?  - 必 须 的
- Ready to kill this son of a bitch?  - Abso-bloody-lutely.
妈的!
Damn it!
糟了
Trouble.
马文!
Marvin!
弗兰克 踩两个踏板 控制两个操纵杆
Frank, it's two pedals and two sticks.
好的
Okay.
妈的! 我们跟丢了 他正在去机场的路上
Damn it! We missed him. He's going into the airport.
去抓他!
Go get him!
- 好的 你们在哪?  - 遇到点麻烦
- Well, where are you?  - In trouble.
请掉头! 你们正处在禁飞区
Turn back! You are in restricted airspace.
弗兰克 他们打算击落我们
Frank, they're gonna blow us outta the sky.
无所谓啊
I wouldn't worry about that.
本来引擎就要熄火了
The engine's shutting down.
求救! 求救!
Mayday! mayday!
弗兰克!
Frank!
我早知道我们要死了!
I knew we were gonna die!
最后一次警告!
This is your last warning!
拜托 告诉我你们坠毁的时候没有带着大规模杀伤性武器吧
Oh, please, tell me you're not crashing with a weapon of mass destruction.
不 弗兰克 不
No, Frank, no.
天啊
Oh, God.
你在后面还好吧 马文?
You okay back there, Marvin?
这可不是个完美的三点降落 弗兰克
It wasn't exactly a three-point landing, Frank.
炸弹怎么样了?
How's the bomb doing?
我无法阻止它
I can't stop it.
我们得把它带出这
We gotta get it outta here.
嘿! 嘿!
Hey! Hey!
给我出来
Get outta the car.
你好啊 弗兰克
Hello, Frank.
欢迎登机
Welcome aboard.
你一直是个好大兵 不是吗?
Always the good soldier, aren't you?
这是个僵局
Stalemate.
怎么才能不伤害她而又干掉他呢?
How will you take him out and not shoot her first?
弗兰克 没关系的
Frank, it's okay.
你能开枪 没关系的
You can shoot. It's okay.
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
给我把枪放下!
Put the gun down!
扔地下!
Drop the gun!
把枪放下 弗兰克
Put the gun down, Frankie.
多谢
Thank you.
你真明智
Pretty smart.
可见爱可以战胜一切
So love does conquer all.
走向你的黄金武士
Go to your golden warrior.
真是个好女孩
That's a good girl.
啊!
Aw!
过来
Come here.
啊! 真幸福
Ah! It's so sweet.
现在下飞机 带着龙葵
Now leave the plane. Take Nightshade with you.
再见了 弗兰克
Bye, Frank.
好梦哦
Sweet dreams.
你为什么不开枪?
Why didn't you just shoot me?
- 出什么事了?  - 我无法解除炸弹
- What happened?  - I couldn't disarm it.
妈的
Oh, crap.
马文
Marvin,
快爆炸了?
it's going to detonate?
是的
Yeah.
抱着我
Put your arms around me.
哦...
Oh...
出我所料
I didn't see that one coming.
这可不是每天都能看到的
There's something you don't see every day.
你把炸弹放在飞机上了
You put the bomb on the plane.
而且 嗯 你还不打算告诉我?
And, um, you didn't think to mention that?
你炸了我的飞机
You blew up my plane.
对不起
Sorry.
我错啦? 我们不会死了吗?
I was wrong? So we're not even gonna die?
目前不会
Not yet.
我真的开始有点喜欢你了 我甚至不打算杀你了
I was actually starting to like you. I was even thinking about not killing you.
当你试图拯救世界的时候 这是理所当然的
This is what happens when you try to save the world.
韩 韩 这事儿
Han. Han, you can't
- 没法用钱算的  - 不 不
- put a price on these things.  - Uh-uh.
你欠我三千万的飞机钱 还有两千万不杀你的钱
You owe me 30 million for the plane. And 20 for not killing you.
你死定了 摩西
You're a dead man, Moses.
谢谢你
Thanks for your help.
真的
Really.
你觉得他是认真的吗?
You think he means it?
没 他是个好小伙
Nah, he's a nice guy.
我是认真的 弗兰克!
I mean it, Frank!
好吧
All right.
啊!
Aw!
他们会非常幸福的
They're going to be right as rain.
话说他真能提供一个安全的港湾
He made the run to emotional safety.
那么...
So...
我听说在加拉加斯有份工作
I did hear about this job in Caracas.
然后呢?
And?
别看我 她是你的女朋友
Don't look at me. She's your girlfriend.
哦
Oh.
走吧
Come on.